lan Matsumoto

DATA ANALYST

https://github.com/ianmat55 808-679-7230 ianmat55@gmail.com

PROFILE

lan Matsumoto is a GIS Analyst, freelancer and programmer. Travelling to the Bay Area from his hometown of Honolulu HI, Ian is pursuing his passion for creative innovation through a career in technology. He carries with him 5+ years of experience with GIS technologies, a love for computer science, and an exceptional work ethic.

EDUCATION

University of Redlands

Bachelor of Science (2015-2019)

Environmental Science

GIS

Mathematics

SKILLS

Technologies:

GIS based systems

Git

Lidar and remote sensing

Languages:

Python

SOL

HTML/CSS

Some JavaScript

Professional:

QA processing

New hire training

Workflow coordination

Technical writing

EXPERIENCE

Data Annotation Specialist

Tesla | 10/2020 - present

Assist in the training and development of Tesla autopilot ai through the use of GIS and data labeling

- Served as a bottleneck of data labeling for six teams, identifying areas critical to training the neural network
- labled and verified an average of 100 data sets per day in a dynamic workflow
- Serve as a critical asset to the QA team and learned about the general workflow to QA process. Identify and resolve Quality Assurance workflow issues and improvement initiatives.
- Drive teams to improve processes, explicate data and yield meaningful metrics.
- Direct two daily feedback reports for engineering, project management, and leadership teams.

Freelance Web Developer

2/2021 - present

Self-taught programmer specializing in website development using Wordpress and Shopify.

- Create websites for a running total of three clients on Wordpress and Shopify
- Work with hosting platforms, content management systems and APIs
- Specialize in commerce development as well as personal/professional website development

GIS Analyst

Apple via Apex Systems (Contract)| 07/2019 - 09/2020

Used GIS software to mark construction projects that would affect routing or address changes in Apple Maps

- Conduct web research on construction projects and track their progress through Apple's GIS software
- Responsible for updated and tracking maps in Riverside,
 San Bernardino, and Orange County
- Monitor traffic and pedestrian density on maps to identify areas of potential construction
- Communicate and collaborate with city/county officials, private companies and peers regarding new projects